A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program, Program Director, Office Files of Shepard Forman FA717
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Background Files, 1980-1991; I
  - Philippines - HR&G meeting, Jan. 28 – Feb. 1, 1991 Philippines, 1991 January 28 - February 1 (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 2)
  - HR&G Program Review, 1991 February 11 (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 3)
  - Program Review, 1990 March 12 (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 4)
  - FY 1989 Program Review (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 5)
  - USIAP Program Review, 1989 October (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 6)
  - HR&G Program Review - Rapparteur Notes, 1988 October (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 7)
  - May 1988/1987 DCP Summary Tables, 1987-1988 (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 8)
  - DCP Review, 1986 October (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 9)
  - Human Rights & Governance Program Review, 1986 (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 10)
  - Human Rights & Governance Program Review, 1985 November (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 11)
  - Work/Family Task Force Subcommittee (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 12)
- AIDS Background Files, 1987-1988; II
  Series II, AIDS Background Files, 1987-1988, includes proposals, background materials for meetings, publications, memos, and correspondence.
  - AIDS Background - AIDS Action Council (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 1)
  - AIDS Background - AIDS in India (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 2)
  - AIDS Background - Dane County Forum (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 3)
  - AIDS Background - HIV in Women (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 4)
  - AIDS Background - H.R. Campaign Fund Vic Basile (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 5)
  - AIDS Background - Center for Population Options (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 6)
  - AIDS Background - Centers for Disease Control (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 7)
  - AIDS Background - Citizens Commission On AIDS (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 8)
  - AIDS Background - Fund for the City of New York (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 9)
  - AIDS Background - International Development Research Center (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 10)
  - AIDS Background - Harrison McKay (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 11)
  - AIDS Background - Symposium – Mass Panic (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 12)
  - AIDS Background - National Commission To Prevent Infant Mortality (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 13)
  - AIDS Background - National Puerto Rican Coalition (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 14)
  - AIDS Background - June Osborn article (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 15)
  - AIDS Background - PATH – Prog. Appropriate Technology in Health (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 16)
  - AIDS Background - Red Cross (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 17)
  - AIDS Background - Science & Technology Article (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 18)
  - AIDS – Criminal Justice Proposals - Association for Bar of City of New York Fund, Inc. (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 19)
  - AIDS – Criminal Justice Proposals - The Legal Aid Society (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 20)
  - AIDS – Criminal Justice Proposals - Mark Moore-Harvard JFK School (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 21)
  - AIDS – Criminal Justice Proposals - National Institute of Justice (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 22)
  - AIDS-DCP - R. Horovitz (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 23)
  - AIDS-DCP - AIDS – Africa (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 24)
  - AIDS-DCP - AIDS – Mexico (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 25)
  - AIDS-DCP - GAPA (Support Group for the Prevention of AIDS) (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 26)
  - AIDS-DCP - Haitain Coalition of AIDS (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 27)
  - AIDS-DCP - AIDS – Haiti (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 28)
  - AIDS – General Impact Assessment Proposals - Stephen Graubard – DAEDALUS (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 29)
  - AIDS – General Impact Assessment Proposals - Walter Reich, MD National Security Studies Center (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 30)
  - AIDS – General Impact Assessment Proposals - SRRC(Social Science Research Council) (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 31)
  - AIDS – Local Initiatives Proposals - Edgar Cahn (Service Credits) (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 32)
  - AIDS – Local Initiatives Proposals - Corlabs (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 33)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Allied Signal (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 34)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Jane Delgado – COSSMHO (National Coalition of Hispanic Health and Human Services Organization) (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 35)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Dr. Beny Primm (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 36)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Project Hope (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 37)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Anne Welbourne – Moglia NYU (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 38)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Oralee Wachter (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 39)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - Rochelle Zeidman – American Red Cross (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 40)
  - AIDS – Proposals, Public Education for Prevention - AIDS Education – Misc. (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 41)
  - AIDS – Research - Foundation Center (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 42)
  - AIDS – Research - Dan Fax/ David Willis (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 43)
  - AIDS – Adolescents (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 44)
  - AIDS – Costs (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 45)
  - AIDS – Dispute Resolution (Box 8 (SK #33358), Folder 46)
  - AIDS Files - School of Dentistry (University of California) (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 1)
  - AIDS Files - Rosemary Passontino (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 2)
  - AIDS Files - Rodger Max- Barrow (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 3)
  - AIDS Files - David Hallman – United Church of Canada (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 4)
  - AIDS Files - John Wolfe – AIDS Project (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 5)
  - AIDS Files - Vermont C.A.R.E.S. (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 6)
  - AIDS Files - Gerald Hursch-Cesar – Intercultural Communications (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 7)
  - Subject: Politics of AIDS - C. Everett Koop address (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 8)
  - Subject: Politics of AIDS - Helms Amendment Background (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 9)
  - Subject: Politics of AIDS - Politics of AIDS (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 10)
  - Subject: Politics of AIDS - National Conference of State Legislators (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 11)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Resources available (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 12)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Mario Orlandi – American Health Foundation (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 13)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - SSRC (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 14)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Citizens Commission On AIDS (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 15)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Nicholas Raugo (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 16)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Abigail Krystall (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 17)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Henry Mosley – Johns Hopkins University (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 18)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Henry Mosley – Johns Hopkins University (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 19)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - D.C. Jayasuriga (includes c.v.) (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 20)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Robert Wood Johnson (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 21)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - R. Faden – Johns Hopkins University (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 22)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Dr. Jellinik - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 23)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Congress of National Black Churches (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 24)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Lincoln Chen, Harvard – School of Public Health (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 25)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Harvard School, School of Public Health (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 26)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - Dr. Sam Matheny – Health Resources Services Administration (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 27)
  - Subject: AIDS Resource People - George Marshall Worthington (includes resumes) (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 28)
  - Subject: AIDS Rights and Protection - London Meeting – AIDS, 1988 March (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 29)
  - Subject: AIDS Rights and Protection - Center for Constitutional Rights (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 30)
  - Subject: AIDS Rights and Protection - Legal Action Center (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 31)
  - Subject: AIDS Rights and Protection - Robert Stein – Environmental Mediation International (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 32)
  - Subject: AIDS Rights and Protection - AIDS Treatment and Drugs (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 33)
  - Original AIDS Letter (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 34)
  - Responses to AIDS letters (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 35)
  - AIDS Letters with Precis (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 36)
  - AIDS Fund Committee (Box 9 (SK #33054), Folder 37)
  - Subject: Consultants/AIDS - Consultant Assignments (includes c.v.) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 1)
  - Subject: Consultants/AIDS - Memos re: consultants reports (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 2)
  - Subject: Consultants/AIDS - General (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 3)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Carter Center (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 4)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Conference of Mayors (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 5)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Family Health International (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 6)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - FF memos, etc. (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 7)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Foundation Center (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 8)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Harvard – School of Public Health (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 9)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Jan Friedman – Investment Research – AIDS (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 10)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Roger Laut – Salzburg Seminar (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 11)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Mainstream article (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 12)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - National Academy of Sciences (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 13)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Presidential Commission Report (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 14)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - ABFE (Assn. Of Black Foundation Executives) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 15)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - SIPI (Scientists Institute for Public Information) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 16)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - Non-Governmental Organization (NGO) Committee on UNICEF (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 17)
  - Subject: General Files – AIDS - G. W. Worthington – NGO Committee on UNICEF (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 18)
  - Subject: Legal and Ethical Issues - David Schalman – Testimony for Presidential Committee on H.I.V. epidemic (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 19)
  - Subject: Legal and Ethical Issues - Hastings Center (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 20)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - Citizens Panel (NY/NJ) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 21)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 22)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - David Dinkins (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 23)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - NYC Health Dept. (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 24)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - NY Community Trust (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 25)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - NY Urban Trust (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 26)
  - Subject: AIDS NYC - Siecus Report (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 27)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Carnegie Foundation (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 28)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Edna McConnell Clark (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 29)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Foundation Center (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 30)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Donor's Mtg – Kenya (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 31)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Walter & Elsie Haas Fund (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 32)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - MacArthur Foundation (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 33)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Josiah Macy Foundation (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 34)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 35)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Minority Task Force (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 36)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - NYRAG (National Regional Assn. Of Grantmakers) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 37)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - PEW (Rebecca Rinel) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 38)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Population Council Meeting (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 39)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Mark Smith, M.D. (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 40)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Natalie Spinganen (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 41)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Nancy Tichten – Bankers' Trust (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 42)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Jerold Weitzman – Exxon (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 43)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Terry Mooney – WHO (World Health Organization) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 44)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Manuel Corballo - WHO (World Health Organization) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 45)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Jonathan Mann - WHO (World Health Organization) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 46)
  - Subject: AIDS – Other Funders - Other Funders (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 47)
  - Subject: Policy - George Washington University (R. Merritt) (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 48)
  - Subject: Public Policy - ACLU – AIDS Task Force (Box 10 (SK #33055), Folder 49)
  - Subject: Public Policy - General Correspondence AIDS (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 1)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Files (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 2)
  - Subject: Public Policy - AIDS Conference - Stockholm, Sweden, 1988 June 11 - 17 (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 3)
  - Subject: Public Policy - General (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 4)
  - Subject: Public Policy - AIDS – Funding Mechanism Committee (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 5)
  - Subject: Public Policy - AMFAR (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 6)
  - Subject: Public Policy - AIDS Testimony (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 7)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Presidential Commission on AIDS (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 8)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Presidential Commission on HIV Epidemic and National Leadership Coalition on AIDS. Washington, D.C., 1988 February 24 (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 9)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Testimony presented at the Presidential Commission on AIDS – Washington, D.C., 1988 April 19 (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 10)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Council on Foundations AIDS meeting – Washington, D.C., 1988 February 18 (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 11)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Tom Wahman – Rockefeller Bros. Fund, 1988 February 1 (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 12)
  - Subject: Public Policy - Original AIDS report (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 13)
  - Subject: Public Policy - June Osborn Speech (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 14)
  - Subject: Public Policy - General (Box 11 (SK #33056), Folder 15)
- General Correspondence Files, 1981-1982; III
  Series III, General Correspondence Files, 1981-1982, is comprised of general correspondence written to and by Forman on various topics including legal services, consultants, human rights, and grant correspondence.
  - Meetings and agendas, 1981-1982 (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 1)
  - Legal Services – Back-up Centers (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 2)
  - Proposals - Rejection Letters (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 3)
  - Shepard Forman General Correspondence I, 1981-1982 (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 4)
  - Shepard Forman General Correspondence II, 1981-1982 (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 5)
  - Shepard Forman General Correspondence III, 1981-1982 (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 6)
  - Reproductive Health Committee – Human Rights, 1982 (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 7)
  - Consultants (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 8)
  - Human Rights (external of USA) (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 9)
  - Human Rights (internal USA) (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 10)
  - Grants – Rejection Letters (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 11)
  - DAG, 1981 (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 12)
  - Grant correspondence, memos, etc. (Box 12 (SK #34247), Folder 13)
- General Files, 1985-1992; IV
  Series IV, General Files, 1985-1992, is comprised of correspondence, project proposals, meeting notes, consultant reports, and discussion papers. Of note are materials pertaining to the promotion of pluralism and diversity in the areas of public policy and international affairs.
  - European Foundation Centre - Central and East European Publishing Project (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 1)
  - European Cultural Foundation - East-West Parlimentary Practice Project - Jill Adler (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 2)
  - European Cultural Foundation - East West Parlimentary Practice Project Meeting (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 3)
  - European Cooperation Fund (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 4)
  - European Cooperation Fund - Fund for book publication in East and Central European Languages (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 5)
  - European Cooperation Fund - Minutes to Meeting, 1986 April 8 (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 6)
  - European Cooperation Fund - Central European Publishing Project, 1986 October 27 (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 7)
  - European Cooperation Fund - Central European Publishing Project, 1990-1992 (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 8)
  - European Cooperation Fund - Eastern European Publications (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 9)
  - IRCA (Immigration Reform and Control Act) (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 10)
  - Ford Foundation Review of Programs related to pluralism and diversity (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 11)
  - Susan Subak Report: A Survey of US Environmental Organizations (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 12)
  - Don Robinson Report: Bicentennial Era Plans and Opportunities (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 13)
  - Draft Report: Immigration and Human Captial/Ray Marshall (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 14)
  - Shane Hunt Report: Grad Programs in Applied Economics and Public Policy/Chile and Argentina (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 15)
  - Legislative Parlimentary Exchange (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 16)
  - Consultant Report: Fostering Diversity in Public Television (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 17)
  - Michael Chege - Gpp East and South Africa (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 18)
  - Professor Larry Fuchs - Immigration & Refugee Issues (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 19)
  - Christine Harrington - Dispute Resolution (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 20)
  - Marvin Harris - Anthropology (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 21)
  - John Hardt/William Robinson - Congressional Research Service (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 22)
  - Louise Lampere - Changing Relations Project (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 23)
  - William Lesher - Common Good (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 24)
  - Robert Michael - Harris School of Public Policy (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 25)
  - A. Perlmutter - Bill of Rights Project (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 26)
  - Robert Russell - Consultant (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 27)
  - Donna Shalala - Madison Plan (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 28)
  - Changing Relations Project (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 29)
  - Changing Relations Project (2nd folder) (Box 13 (SK #39825), Folder 30)
  - Think Tank Files (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 1)
  - Minority Pipeline (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 2)
  - Program for Minority Recruitment and Training in Public Policy and International Affairs (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 3)
  - 1990 Census on Minority Political Participation (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 4)
  - Evaluation of Alfred P. Sloan Minority Public Policy Careers Program (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 5)
  - Black Church (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 6)
  - Black Organizations and Fundraising (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 7)
  - Individual Papers: Peter Yu - Papers on affirmative action and the American Electoral System Tonya Lewis - paper on voter registration Catherine Castoreno - paper on US Hispanics Rhona Rapoport - paper on external affirmative action S. Forman, Bentsi-Enchill - paper on the Human Rights and Governance Program Rhona Rapoport - Notes from Geneva and Paper on Improving Government Dru Findley - paper on recent events in China Mora McLean - paper on human rights in Africa (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 8)
  - ACLU - Perlmutter Production (Handwritten Notes) (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 9)
  - Perlmutter Production - Sweet Land of Liberty (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 10)
  - ACLS - Comparative Perspectives on the U.S. Constitution (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 11)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (1961 Paper on the Fund for the Republic) (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 12)
  - CIEPLAN Analysis by Steve Sanderson (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 13)
  - Economic Policy Institute (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 14)
  - Luxembourg Income Study (LIS) (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 15)
  - Maxwell School Syracuse University/Biographical Sketches (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 16)
  - NALEO - Report on Recently Naturalized Individuals (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 17)
  - National Council of La Raza (Mission Statement) (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 18)
  - Draft Report on first decade of La Raza (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 19)
  - La Raza - Financial Review (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 20)
  - SSRC: Contemporary Hispanic Issues (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 21)
  - Tomas Rivera Center: 2 reports on improving delivery of services to immigrants (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 22)
  - Tomas Rivera Center: Funding Agenda (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 23)
  - Urban Institute: Report by Tom Anton (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 24)
  - Urban Institute: Changing Domestic Priorities (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 25)
  - Papers on problems and opportunities in Governance and Economics, 1979 (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 26)
  - Congressional Research Service (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 27)
  - Exchange 2000 (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 28)
  - Humphrey Institute (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 29)
  - Reproductive Health - Geneva, 1990 (Box 14 (SK#39826), Folder 30)
- Trip Files, 1981-1990; V
  Series V, Trip Files, 1981-1990, mainly consists of itineraries, reading materials for meetings, agendas, handwritten notes, and lists of participants of meetings attended by Forman. Also included in a smaller amount are meeting proceedings, lists of grants, and strategy papers.
  - European Trip, 1981 April (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 1)
  - Philippines Meeting, 1982 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 2)
  - South Africa Trip File, 1982 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 3)
  - European (London/Paris), 1983 October (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 4)
  - Bellagio Conference (Institute for Research on Poverty/U-WI), 1984 May 14 - 17 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 5)
  - Washington, D.C. – GPP/Welfare State – Program Discussions, 1984 June 13 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 6)
  - Nairobi: HR & G, 1985 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 7)
  - Center for Mexican American Studies, 1985 May 21 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 8)
  - Paris – Amsterdam Brussels, 1985 June 16 – 21 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 9)
  - IAP Rio Meeting, 1985 June – July (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 10)
  - Texas, 1987 February 7-10 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 11)
  - China, 1987 August 2 - 18 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 12)
  - Washington, D. C., 1987 March 5 - 6 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 13)
  - Africa/Latin America – D. Arnold, 1987 March (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 14)
  - Southwest with H. Ramos/West Coast, 1987 April 28 - May 6 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 15)
  - Europe, 1987 Summer (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 16)
  - Washington – Brookings/Urban Institute, 1987 July 7 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 17)
  - California, 1987 October (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 18)
  - Atlanta/Miami: Board Meeting, 1987 October 4 - 8 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 19)
  - Kansas City, MO (Hispanic Development Fund Project), 1988 December 9 - 10 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 20)
  - Washington, D.C., 1987 December 17 - 18 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 21)
  - The Johnson Foundation: WINGSPREAD, 1987 (Box 15 (SK #38319), Folder 22)
  - Montreal: AIDS Coalition, 1989 June 4 - 9 (Box 16 (SK #38675), Folder 1)
  - Washington, D.C.: NCAP, 1989 June 20 (Box 16 (SK #38675), Folder 2)
  - Washington, D.C., 1989 May 10 - 11 (Box 16 (SK #38675), Folder 3)
  - Berlin: ACLS, 1989 September (Box 16 (SK #38675), Folder 4)
  - Senegal, 1989 September (Box 16 (SK #38675), Folder 5)